(Watch on www.kisskh.xyz Support Admin)
(شاهد على www.kisskh.xyz دعم الإدارة)
The Xing Dynasty is powerful and prosperous.
كانت سلالة شينغ قوية ومزدهرة.
It has been dominant in the Central Plains for a hundred years.
لقد كانت مهيمنة في السهول الوسطى لمدة مئة عام.
The northern Khan Su He of the Talhan
خان سو هي الشمالي من تلهان
led his fierce and warlike tribesmen to repeatedly invade the border.
قاد رجال قبيلته الشرسين والمحاربين لغزو الحدود مراراً وتكراراً.
The fifth prince of Xing Dynasty, Yin Qi, was ordered by the emperor to quell the rebellion.
أُمر الأمير الخامس لسلالة شينغ، يين تشي، من قبل الإمبراطور بإخماد التمرد.
Three years later,
بعد ثلاث سنوات،
the border regions returned to peace.
عادت المناطق الحدودية إلى السلام.
However.
لكن.
Su He's ambition remained unabated.
لم يثنِ طموح سو هي شيء.
He conspired with Yin Zhou, the eldest prince of the Xing Dynasty.
لقد تآمر مع يين تشو، الأمير الأكبر لسلالة شينغ.
He intended to usurp the throne.
كان ينوي اغتصاب العرش.
And overthrow the government.
وإسقاط الحكومة.
The fifth prince arrives
وصول الأمير الخامس
to meet the emperor.
للقاء الإمبراطور.
Who dares to stop us?
من يجرؤ على إيقافنا؟
We've been ordered by Prince Fengsun
لقد تلقينا أوامر من الأمير فنغسون
to take your lives here.
أن تقتلوا أرواحكم هنا.
Fellow soldiers,
أيها الجنود الزملاء،
follow me to kill the traitors.
اتبعني لقتل الخونة.
And rescue the emperor!
وأنقذوا الإمبراطور!
Your Highness
صاحب السمو
Khan.
خان.
Yin Qi has indeed returned with a troop.
لقد عاد يين تشي بالفعل مع فرقة من الجنود.
He is outside the imperial palace
هو خارج القصر الإمبراطوري
fighting with Khan's men.
القتال مع رجال خان.
It seems he will break into the imperial palace soon.
يبدو أنه سيقتحم القصر الإمبراطوري قريباً.
To His Royal Highness, the Crown Prince.
إلى صاحب السمو الملكي ولي العهد.
No.
لا.
It should be the future Emperor of Daxing.
ينبغي أن يكون هو إمبراطور داكسينغ المستقبلي.
This night's drama.
أحداث هذه الليلة الدرامية.
I have been waiting for a long time.
لقد كنت أنتظر منذ وقت طويل.
What a pity for your nephew.
يا للأسف على ابن أخيك.
He has always believed
لطالما آمن
that I would spare him and Yin Qi.
أنني سأبقي عليه وعلى يين تشي.
Little does he know
لا يعلم ذلك
that he is just my hunter.
أنه مجرد صيادي.
Once he has hunted Yin Qi for me.
بمجرد أن يصطاد لي يين تشي.
I will grant his wish
سأحقق أمنيته
and send him and Yin Qi to the netherworld together.
وأرسله هو و يين تشي إلى العالم السفلي معًا.
I have heard long ago
سمعت ذلك منذ زمن بعيد
that your fifth younger brother has been close friends with my nephew for many years.
أن أخاك الخامس الأصغر كان صديقاً مقرباً لابن أخي لسنوات عديدة.
Will he really turn against my nephew because of a forged letter?
هل سينقلب حقاً على ابن أخي بسبب رسالة مزورة؟
Being betrayed by someone you've been with day and night for years
أن تتعرض للخيانة من شخص كنت معه ليلاً ونهاراً لسنوات
is not a pleasant feeling.
ليس شعوراً ممتعاً.
I want to see Yin Qi lose everything with my own eyes.
أريد أن أرى يين تشي يخسر كل شيء بأم عيني.
To kill the only person in this world who still cares about himwith my own hands.
أن أقتل الشخص الوحيد في هذا العالم الذي لا يزال يهتم لأمره بيدي.
Such a wonderful drama
يا لها من دراما رائعة
deserves such fine wine indeed.
يستحق هذا النبيذ الفاخر حقاً.
It's time for him to make an appearance.
حان الوقت ليظهر.
The Emperor was clearly in the secret chamber we arranged.
كان الإمبراطور موجوداً بوضوح في الغرفة السرية التي رتبناها.
How could he be gone?
كيف يمكن أن يكون قد رحل؟
Hurry up and find him!
أسرعوا وابحثوا عنه!
No need to search.
لا حاجة للبحث.
We've already
لقد فعلنا ذلك بالفعل
killed the old Emperor.
قتل الإمبراطور العجوز.
How dare you disobey my orders?
كيف تجرؤ على عصيان أوامري؟
Act on your own accord.
تصرف بمحض إرادتك.
Fengsun.
فنغسون.
Do you really think the Khan would entrust
هل تعتقد حقاً أن الخان سيثق
the old Emperor's life
حياة الإمبراطور العجوز
into your hands?
بين يديك؟
Hand over the Talhan's military talisman obediently.
سلّم التميمة العسكرية الخاصة بعائلة طلهان بطاعة .
The Khan might spare you out of respect for your father
قد يعفو عنك الخان احتراماً لوالدك
and not kill you.
ولن يقتلك.
It's not for you to demand the talisman from me.
ليس من حقك أن تطلب مني التميمة.
Where are Su He and Yin Zhou?
أين سو هي وين تشو؟
I want to see them.
أريد رؤيتهم.
His life belongs to me.
حياته ملكي.
Qi.
تشي.
Why are you here?
لماذا أنت هنا؟
[Letter indicating plans to kill the emperor in five days]
[رسالة تشير إلى خطط لقتل الإمبراطور خلال خمسة أيام]
If I hadn't obtained this secret letter.
لو لم أحصل على هذه الرسالة السرية.
I wouldn't have seen your true colors.
ما كنت لأرى حقيقتك.
Hand over the talisman first.
سلّم التميمة أولاً.
Then I'll send you both to hell.
ثم سأرسلكما إلى الجحيم.
Qi.
تشي.
Pei Yanzhi.
باي يانزي.
No
لا
I should call you Fengsun.
ينبغي أن أناديكِ فينغسون.
The person I trusted most
الشخص الذي أثق به أكثر من غيره
turned out to be a spy sent by Talhan.
اتضح أنه جاسوس أرسله طلهان.
Today
اليوم
I will kill you with my own hands.
سأقتلك بيدي.
What?
ماذا؟
Do it!
افعلها!
Qi.
تشي.
Leave here quickly
غادر من هنا بسرعة
I'll explain everything to you after tonight.
سأشرح لك كل شيء بعد الليلة.
But right now.
لكن الآن.
If you don't leave now, it'll be too late.
إذا لم تغادر الآن، فسيكون الوقت قد فات.
Yin Qi, the fifth prince of Xing Dynasty, colluded with the hostage Fengsun
تواطأ يين تشي، الأمير الخامس لسلالة شينغ، مع الرهينة فنغسون
intending to usurp the throne.
ينوي اغتصاب العرش.
By [planning to] assassinate the Emperor at the Southern Palace.
عن طريق [التخطيط لـ] اغتيال الإمبراطور في القصر الجنوبي.
Fortunately,
لحسن الحظ،
the Crown Prince
ولي العهد
risked his life
خاطر بحياته
to rescue the Emperor
لإنقاذ الإمبراطور
and slew the two traitors.
وقتل الخائنين الاثنين.
This drama of failing to protect the king,
هذه الدراما التي تدور حول الفشل في حماية الملك،
killing the traitors,
قتل الخونة،
and ascending to the throne
والصعود إلى العرش
is truly splendid.
إنه رائع حقاً.
I haven't been able to kill him in these three years.
لم أتمكن من قتله خلال هذه السنوات الثلاث.
If I hadn't lured him back using Pei Yanzhi and eliminated him in one fell swoop,
لو لم أقم باستدراجه باستخدام باي يانزي والقضاء عليه بضربة واحدة،
he would have
كان سيفعل
become a major threat in the future.
سيصبح تهديداً كبيراً في المستقبل.
I thought
ظننت
going to the border would bring peace to the realm.
إن الذهاب إلى الحدود سيجلب السلام إلى المملكة.
Yet I didn't expect,
لكنني لم أتوقع ذلك.
in just three years,
في غضون ثلاث سنوات فقط،
upon my return,
عند عودتي،
I didn't even get to see my father's face one last time.
لم أتمكن حتى من رؤية وجه والدي للمرة الأخيرة.
My best friend became a traitor for Daxing.
أصبح صديقي المقرب خائناً لصالح داكسينغ.
My brother
أخي
killed his own brother and father.
قتل أخاه ووالده.
Yin Zhou,
يين تشو,
can you sit on this throne
هل يمكنك الجلوس على هذا العرش؟
stained with blood in peace?
ملطخة بالدماء في سلام؟
Your skills in archery come from me and my teaching.
مهاراتك في الرماية تأتي مني ومن تدريبي.
Let me see how well you've learned.
دعني أرى مدى جودة تعلمك.
Qi.
تشي.
Hurry up.
أسرع.
Colorful sleeves eagerly hold jade cups.
أكمام ملونة تحمل أكواب اليشم بشغف.
See how rosy-cheeked we were in our drunken revelry.
انظروا كيف كانت وجوهنا وردية اللون في احتفالاتنا الصاخبة.
Dancing until the moon sinks behind the willow trees.
الرقص حتى يغيب القمر خلف أشجار الصفصاف.
Singing until the wind fades beneath the peach blossom fans.
يغنون حتى تهدأ الرياح تحت مراوح زهر الخوخ.
Since our parting,
منذ فراقنا،
I recall our meetings,
أتذكر اجتماعاتنا،
dreaming of you countless times.
أحلم بك مرات لا تحصى.
Tonight, I hold up the silver lamp,
الليلة، أرفع المصباح الفضي،
fearing our meeting is but a dream.
أخشى أن يكون لقاؤنا مجرد حلم.
Let me see
دعني أرى
what you're wearing around your neck.
ما ترتديه حول رقبتك.
You can't touch this wolf tooth pendant.
لا يمكنك لمس هذه القلادة المصنوعة من سن الذئب.
This is a keepsake from the White-Eyed Wolf King
هذه هدية تذكارية من ملك الذئاب ذي العيون البيضاء
for his beloved.
لحبيبته.
It can bless two lovers to
يمكن أن يبارك ذلك عاشقين لـ
be together for all eternity.
ليبقى كل منهما معاً إلى الأبد.
"Journey With You"
"رحلة معك"
(Episode 1)
(الحلقة 1)
Has His Highness not awakened yet?
ألم يستيقظ صاحب السمو بعد؟
Not yet,
ليس بعد،
but don't worry,
لكن لا تقلق،
I'm here.
أنا هنا.
This is Yonghe Palace,
هذا قصر يونغهي،
I'm not dead.
أنا لست ميتاً.
No,
لا،
this can't be.
هذا غير معقول.
That arrow clearly hit me in the chest.
لقد أصابني هذا السهم بوضوح في صدري.
What on earth is going on?
ما الذي يحدث بحق السماء؟
Qi,
تشي،
you've finally awakened.
لقد استيقظت أخيراً.
You,
أنت،
don't touch me.
لا تلمسني.
Pei Yanzhi,
باي يانزي,
you traitor.
يا خائن.
Qi,
تشي،
you're confused from your illness.
أنت تشعر بالارتباك بسبب مرضك.
Today,
اليوم،
I must kill you
يجب أن أقتلك
to avenge my father.
للثأر لأبي.
Qi,
تشي،
what's wrong with you?
ما مشكلتك؟
Thank goodness,
شكرا لله،
Your Highness has finally awakened.
لقد استيقظ سموكم أخيراً.
Do you feel better?
هل تشعر بتحسن؟
The fever has subsided,
انخفضت الحمى،
but it worried me greatly.
لكن ذلك أقلقني كثيراً.
Just now, the Imperial Concubine asked me
قبل قليل، سألتني المحظية الإمبراطورية
if Your Highness had awakened.
لو أن سموكم قد استيقظ.
What did you say?
ماذا قلت؟
My mother,
أمي،
she's still alive?
هل ما زالت على قيد الحياة؟
Your Highness must be confused from sleep
لا بد أن سموكم في حالة ارتباك بسبب النوم
to say such nonsense.
أن يقول المرء مثل هذا الهراء.
Qi,
تشي،
Mother is seriously ill,
الأم مريضة بشدة،
I've returned to three years ago.
لقد عدت إلى ما قبل ثلاث سنوات.
Brother, you've awakened.
يا أخي، لقد استيقظت.
Heshu, you're here too.
هيشو، أنت هنا أيضاً.
That's good,
هذا جيد،
that's good.
هذا جيد.
Where else would I be if not here?
أين سأكون إن لم أكن هنا؟
Since you've awakened,
منذ أن استيقظت،
come with me to visit Mother quickly.
تعال معي لزيارة أمي بسرعة.
What's wrong with you?
ما مشكلتك؟
Are you feeling unwell?
هل تشعر بتوعك؟
Should I call the imperial physician?
هل يجب أن أتصل بالطبيب الإمبراطوري؟
Heshu,
هيشو،
I'm fine.
أنا بخير.
Come,
يأتي،
let's go visit Mother quickly.
هيا بنا نزور أمي بسرعة.
Mother.
الأم.
Qi,
تشي،
you've awakened,
لقد استيقظت،
I can rest easy now.
يمكنني أن أرتاح الآن.
Mother
الأم
why are you crying again?
لماذا تبكين مجدداً؟
A man doesn't shed tears easily.
الرجل لا يذرف الدموع بسهولة.
Mother.
الأم.
I just miss you so much.
أشتاق إليك كثيراً.
I really miss you.
أنا حقاً أفتقدك.
You,
أنت،
still such a child.
لا يزال طفلاً.
Heshu,
هيشو،
what day is it today?
ما هو اليوم؟
The tenth day of the seventh month.
اليوم العاشر من الشهر السابع.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
how could you forget this?
كيف يُمكنك أن تنسى هذا؟
The tenth day of the seventh month
اليوم العاشر من الشهر السابع
is the day before Mother passed away.
كان ذلك في اليوم السابق لوفاة والدتي.
Mother can't keep coughing like this.
لا يمكن للأم أن تستمر في السعال هكذا.
Brother,
أخ،
let's go ask Father.
هيا بنا نسأل أبي.
He loves Mother so much,
إنه يحب أمه كثيراً،
he'll surely find the best doctors in the land for her.
سيجد لها بالتأكيد أفضل الأطباء في البلاد.
Maybe then Mother's illness will be cured.
لعل مرض أمي سيُشفى حينها.
Don't go,
لا تذهب،
Heshu.
هيشو.
Qi.
تشي.
Mother doesn't have much time left.
لم يتبق للأم الكثير من الوقت.
You must stay and keep me company.
يجب أن تبقى وتؤنسني.
Mother, don't say that.
يا أمي، لا تقولي ذلك.
I know what kind of state I'm in.
أعرف الحالة التي أنا فيها.
I don't want to face him at this time.
لا أريد مواجهته في هذا الوقت.
As long as you're by Mother's side,
طالما أنت بجانب والدتك،
I'll be content.
سأكون راضياً.
Brother, brother!
يا أخي، يا أخي!
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Why did you make me come back on this day?
لماذا أجبرتني على العودة في هذا اليوم؟
Why couldn't I have stayed with Mother for a few more days?
لماذا لم أستطع البقاء مع أمي لبضعة أيام أخرى؟
Why couldn't you give me more time?
لماذا لم تمنحني المزيد من الوقت؟
Maybe then.
ربما حينها.
Mother wouldn't have died.
ما كانت أمي لتموت.
Qi,
تشي،
Qi
تشي
I know you're hurting,
أعلم أنك تتألم،
but you can't hurt yourself like this.
لكن لا يمكنك أن تؤذي نفسك بهذه الطريقة.
If you need to vent,
إذا كنت بحاجة إلى التنفيس،
punch me instead.
بدلاً من ذلك، اضربني.
Your Highness, Your Highness,
صاحب السمو، صاحب السمو،
something's wrong.
هناك خطب ما.
The Crown Prince has
ولي العهد لديه
suddenly come to visit Concubine Chen.
فجأةً، يأتون لزيارة المحظية تشين.
Almost done, wait a moment.
أوشكنا على الانتهاء، انتظر لحظة.
The Crown Prince arrives.
وصل ولي العهد.
Mother is unwell,
الأم مريضة،
and I must attend to her. I can't entertain guests.
ويجب عليّ أن أعتني بها. لا يمكنني استقبال الضيوف.
Brother, you've come at an inconvenient time.
يا أخي، لقد أتيت في وقت غير مناسب.
Please leave.
يرجى المغادرة.
Heshu,
هيشو،
it's precisely because Concubine Chen is seriously ill
وذلك تحديداً لأن المحظية تشين مريضة بشدة
that I've come on behalf of the Empress to visit her.
أنني جئت نيابة عن الإمبراطورة لزيارتها.
I'm afraid it will disappoint Brother.
أخشى أن يخيب ذلك أمل أخي.
My mother is still alive and well.
والدتي لا تزال على قيد الحياة وبصحة جيدة.
When she recovers in a few days,
عندما تتعافى في غضون أيام قليلة،
she'll personally pay her respects to the Empress.
ستقوم شخصياً بتقديم واجب العزاء للإمبراطورة.
Heshu, stop!
هيشو، توقف!
How can you speak to your elder brother like that?
كيف يمكنك التحدث إلى أخيك الأكبر بهذه الطريقة؟
Heshu is right.
هيشو محق.
Since Brother has already seen Mother,
بما أن الأخ قد رأى الأم بالفعل،
please leave now.
يرجى المغادرة الآن.
Concubine Chen has truly raised a fine daughter and son.
لقد ربت المحظية تشين ابنة وابناً رائعين حقاً.
Are you alright, Mother?
هل أنتِ بخير يا أمي؟
Qi, Qi.
تشي، تشي.
Stop.
قف.
Come back with me.
عد معي.
I advise you,
أنصحك،
while your mother is still alive,
بينما والدتك لا تزال على قيد الحياة،
spend as much time with her as you can.
اقضِ معها أكبر قدر ممكن من الوقت.
When Concubine Chen passes away,
عندما توفيت المحظية تشين،
you'll regret wasting time arguing with me here.
ستندم على إضاعة وقتك في الجدال معي هنا.
I also advise Brother,
أنصح أخي أيضًا،
those who do evil will reap what they sow.
إن الذين يفعلون الشر سيحصدون ما زرعوه.
One day, you'll face the consequences of your actions.
يوماً ما، ستواجه عواقب أفعالك.
Yin Qi,
يين تشى,
how dare you speak to me like that!
كيف تجرؤ على التحدث معي بهذه الطريقة!
When Concubine Chen dies,
عندما تموت المحظية تشين،
you, the Fifth Prince, will surely be disliked by Father.
أنت، أيها الأمير الخامس، ستكون بالتأكيد مكروهاً من قبل أبي.
Let's see if you dare to be so arrogant then.
لنرى إن كنت ستجرؤ على التكبر إلى هذا الحد.
Move aside!
ابتعدوا جانباً!
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
fighting with the Crown Prince
القتال مع ولي العهد
in Concubine Chen's palace
في قصر المحظية تشين
will surely anger the Emperor
سيثير ذلك غضب الإمبراطور بالتأكيد
if he finds out.
إذا اكتشف الأمر.
He's right.
هو محق.
No one knows what I've been through.
لا أحد يعلم ما مررت به.
If others find out,
إذا علم الآخرون بذلك،
it will only cause trouble.
لن يؤدي ذلك إلا إلى التسبب في المشاكل.
Now that I'm back,
الآن وقد عدت،
I'm not afraid of finding a chance to eliminate Yin Zhou.
لا أخشى إيجاد فرصة للقضاء على يين تشو.
Qi,
تشي،
put down the sword.
ضع السيف.
Mother.
الأم.
After being by Yin Qi's side for so long,
بعد أن رافقت يين تشي لفترة طويلة،
you really think
هل تعتقد حقاً
you're a loyal guard?
هل أنت حارس مخلص؟
Mother
الأم
why are you pretending to be sick to scare your son?
لماذا تتظاهرين بالمرض لإخافة ابنك؟
Heshu,
هيشو،
Mother is worried that you'll act impulsively and
الأم قلقة من أن تتصرف باندفاع و
offend your elder brother.
أغضب أخاك الأكبر.
He's not someone you can afford to offend.
إنه ليس شخصاً يمكنك تحمل إهانته.
Don't forget what happened to your third and fourth elder brothers.
لا تنس ما حدث لأخويك الأكبر الثالث والرابع.
Mother, don't worry.
يا أمي، لا تقلقي.
I know now.
أعرف الآن.
I'll be more careful in the future.
سأكون أكثر حذراً في المستقبل.
Does it hurt?
هل يؤلمك؟
Mother, don't worry.
يا أمي، لا تقلقي.
I'm not hurt.
أنا لست مصاباً.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
Your Highness!
يا صاحب السمو!
You've lost a lot of weight recently.
لقد فقدت الكثير من الوزن مؤخراً.
Please take care of yourself.
أرجو أن تعتني بنفسك.
Duan Yi, Duan Yong!
دوان يي، دوان يونغ!
Yes?
نعم؟
Find a way to investigate Su He's information.
ابحث عن طريقة للتحقق من معلومات سو هي.
The more, the better.
كلما زاد العدد كان ذلك أفضل.
Ziming,
زيمينج،
keep an eye on every move in Mingde Palace for me.
راقب كل تحركات قصر مينغدي من أجلي.
Mingde Palace.
قصر مينغدي.
The Crown Prince has always been somewhat overbearing.
لطالما كان ولي العهد متسلطاً إلى حد ما.
But you've never cared about such things before.
لكنك لم تهتم بمثل هذه الأمور من قبل.
Why suddenly?
لماذا فجأة؟
Yes.
نعم.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Su He is the uncle of Prince Pei.
سو هي هو عم الأمير باي.
If Your Highness wants to investigate Su He,
إذا رغبتم يا صاحب السمو في التحقيق مع سو هي،
why not just ask Pei directly?
لماذا لا تسأل باي مباشرة؟
Don't ask so many questions.
لا تطرح الكثير من الأسئلة.
Just do as I say.
افعل ما أقوله لك.
Your Highness, forgive me.
يا صاحب السمو، سامحني.
I will do my utmost.
سأبذل قصارى جهدي.
By the way,
بالمناسبة،
help me prepare more ice containers and agarwood
ساعدني في تحضير المزيد من أوعية الثلج وخشب العود
outside the palace
خارج القصر
in case of necessity.
في حالة الضرورة.
Ice containers?
حاويات الثلج؟
Just do as I say.
افعل ما أقوله لك.
Understood, Your Highness.
مفهوم يا صاحب السمو.
What's wrong with you today?
ما بك اليوم؟
In the past, when Yin Zhou showed off in front of you,
في الماضي، عندما كان يين تشو يتباهى أمامك،
you just laughed it off.
لقد تجاهلت الأمر بضحكة.
This doesn't seem like something you would do.
لا يبدو هذا شيئًا قد تفعله.
Do you care a lot about your elder brother?
هل تهتم كثيراً بأخيك الأكبر؟
Concubine Chen is seriously ill,
المحظية تشين مريضة بشدة،
and many eyes are watching Yunhe Palace.
وتتجه أنظار كثيرة نحو قصر يونهي.
I know you feel it's unfair for Concubine Chen.
أعلم أنك تشعر بأن هذا غير عادل بحق المحظية تشين.
But Qi, no one knows
لكن تشي، لا أحد يعلم
what will happen
ماذا سيحدث؟
if these words reach the Emperor's ears.
إذا وصلت هذه الكلمات إلى مسامع الإمبراطور.
What I care about is you.
ما يهمني هو أنت.
Why are you being so nice to me now?
لماذا أنت لطيف معي الآن؟
Why are you asking this suddenly?
لماذا تسأل هذا فجأة؟
If one day,
إذا حدث ذلك يوماً ما،
we have to stand on opposite sides,
علينا أن نقف على جانبين متقابلين،
Then we'll
ثم سنفعل
face each other with swords,
يواجهان بعضهما البعض بالسيوف،
fighting to the death.
القتال حتى الموت.
If at that time,
إذا كان ذلك في ذلك الوقت،
I recall
أتذكر
your care for me today,
عنايتك بي اليوم،
What kind of feelings will I have?
ما نوع المشاعر التي سأشعر بها؟
You must be exhausted from taking care of Concubine Chen lately,
لا بد أنك مرهق من رعاية المحظية تشين مؤخراً،
that's why Your Highness is having such strange thoughts.
ولهذا السبب تراود سموكم مثل هذه الأفكار الغريبة.
It's late, Your Highness.
لقد تأخر الوقت يا صاحب السمو.
Please rest early.
يرجى أخذ قسط من الراحة مبكراً.
It's precisely because you're treating me so well now
وذلك تحديداً لأنك تعاملني بشكل جيد للغاية الآن
that I can't believe
لا أصدق ذلك
that the "you" who wanted to kill me in my past life
أن "أنت" الذي أراد قتلي في حياتي الماضية
is the same person standing before me now.
هو نفس الشخص الذي يقف أمامي الآن.
Since Heaven has given me a chance to live again,
بما أن السماء منحتني فرصة للعيش من جديد،
This time,
هذه المرة،
I must change our fate.
يجب أن أغير مصيرنا.
Your Highness, Your Highness.
صاحب السمو، صاحب السمو.
Concubine Chen is not doing well.
المحظية تشين ليست بخير.
Mother.
الأم.
Heshu,
هيشو،
don't be sad.
لا تحزن.
After being trapped in this palace for so many years,
بعد أن ظل محتجزاً في هذا القصر لسنوات عديدة،
I can finally leave now.
أستطيع المغادرة الآن أخيراً.
You should be happy for me.
يجب أن تفرح لأجلي.
Mother,
الأم،
don't worry.
لا تقلق.
I won't cry.
لن أبكي.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
[Since we've parted, I've longed to meet you again;
منذ أن افترقنا، كنت أتوق إلى لقائك مرة أخرى؛
how many times have my soul and dreams journeyed with you?]
كم مرة سافرت روحي وأحلامي معك؟
Qi.
تشي.
Let this strand of hair be buried in Jiangnan for me,
دع هذه الخصلة من شعري تُدفن في جيانغنان من أجلي،
so that my soul can return to my hometown.
حتى تتمكن روحي من العودة إلى مسقط رأسي.
In all my future lives,
في جميع حياتي المستقبلية،
I never want
لا أريد أبداً
to have any connection
أن يكون له أي صلة
with the royal family again.
مع العائلة المالكة مجدداً.
Mother.
الأم.
Concubine.
محظية.
Don't leave me.
لا تتركنى.
Mother.
الأم.
Don't leave me and my elder brother.
لا تتركني أنا وأخي الأكبر.
Concubine Chen.
المحظية تشين.
May you rest in peace.
رحمه الله.
Mother.
الأم.
Your son knows what to do now.
ابنك يعرف ما يجب عليه فعله الآن.
The Virtuous Concubine Su,
المحظية الفاضلة سو،
the vastness of heaven,
اتساع السماء،
may your soul return.
عسى أن تعود إليك روحك.
The Virtuous Concubine Su,
المحظية الفاضلة سو،
the vastness of heaven,
اتساع السماء،
may your soul return.
عسى أن تعود إليك روحك.
The Virtuous Concubine Su,
المحظية الفاضلة سو،
the vastness of heaven,
اتساع السماء،
may your soul return.
عسى أن تعود إليك روحك.
Mother.
الأم.
Elder brother.
الأخ الأكبر.
Why don't we ask Father for mercy
لماذا لا نطلب من الآب الرحمة؟
and have Mother's coffin buried in Jiangnan?
وهل دُفن نعش والدتي في جيانغنان؟
It's not appropriate.
هذا غير لائق.
Father won't agree.
الأب لن يوافق.
For Mother's sake,
من أجل أمي،
we should at least try.
ينبغي علينا على الأقل أن نحاول.
Anyway,
على أي حال،
in front of Father and the Empress,
أمام الأب والإمبراطورة،
do not mention this under any circumstance.
لا تذكر هذا تحت أي ظرف من الظروف.
Nanny Su,
المربية سو،
why only this one container of ice?
لماذا هذه العبوة الواحدة من الثلج فقط؟
This won't be enough.
هذا لن يكون كافياً.
Just now, when I went to the Inner Servants Department,
قبل قليل، عندما ذهبت إلى قسم الخدم الداخليين،
I was deliberately hindered.
لقد تم عرقلتي عمداً.
It's so hot,
الجو حار جداً،
and Concubine might...
وقد تكون المحظية...
These heartless servants!
هؤلاء الخدم عديمو الرحمة!
They must have been instigated by the Empress.
لا بد أن الإمبراطورة هي من حرضت على ذلك.
Only then would they dare to do this.
عندها فقط سيجرؤون على فعل ذلك.
If they won't give it,
إذا لم يقدموه،
I'll go get it myself.
سأذهب لأحضره بنفسي.
Heshu.
هيشو.
Don't do anything
لا تفعل أي شيء
that would upset Mother today.
هذا الأمر سيُزعج أمي اليوم.
I have a way.
لديّ طريقة.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
Bring
يحضر
the ice containers and agarwood
حاويات الثلج وخشب العود
I told you to prepare.
قلت لك أن تستعد.
Your Highness is truly prescient.
إن سموكم يتمتع ببصيرة ثاقبة.
Hurry.
عجل.
Qi.
تشي.
Don't go.
لا تذهب.
The ice containers and agarwood you wanted,
حاويات الثلج وخشب العود الذي كنت تريده،
I've already sent someone to buy them.
لقد أرسلتُ شخصاً بالفعل لشرائها.
These ice containers,
حاويات الثلج هذه،
even with money, we couldn't have bought so many in such a short amount of time.
حتى مع توفر المال، لم نكن لنستطيع شراء كل هذا العدد في مثل هذه الفترة القصيرة من الزمن.
Could it be that you knew in advance
هل من الممكن أنك كنت تعلم مسبقاً؟
that Mother would be hindered?
هل ستتعرض الأم للعرقلة؟
Concubine Chen,
المحظية تشين،
has been deliberately hindered ever since she fell ill.
لقد تم عرقلتها عمداً منذ أن مرضت.
Just in case,
تحسباً لأي طارئ،
I prepared these in advance.
لقد أعددت هذه مسبقاً.
I just didn't expect
لم أتوقع ذلك
that you would think of it too.
أنك ستفكر في ذلك أيضاً.
Did you think I'll be like Heshu,
هل ظننت أنني سأكون مثل هيشو؟
drowning in grief over losing Mother?
هل يغرق المرء في الحزن على فقدان والدته؟
Mother is gone,
رحلت أمي.
I have to be Heshu's pillar of strength.
يجب أن أكون سند هيشو وقوته.
These preemptive measures,
هذه التدابير الاستباقية،
are what I should do.
هذا ما يجب عليّ فعله.
I've definitely seen this emblem in my past life.
لقد رأيت هذا الشعار بالتأكيد في حياتي السابقة.
Fifth Prince,
الأمير الخامس،
are you alright?
هل أنت بخير؟
It's nothing.
لا شئ.
I've already ordered the royal mausoleum to be renovated.
لقد طلبت بالفعل تجديد الضريح الملكي.
After the funeral rites are over,
بعد انتهاء مراسم الجنازة،
Concubine Chen will be sent there.
سيتم إرسال المحظية تشين إلى هناك.
It's also my last gift
إنها أيضاً هديتي الأخيرة
to my beloved concubine.
إلى محظيتي الحبيبة.
Concubine Chen always said she wanted to go back to Jiangnan to see it.
لطالما قالت المحظية تشين إنها تريد العودة إلى جيانغنان لرؤيتها.
In a while,
بعد قليل،
I'll order someone to build
سأطلب من شخص ما أن يبني
a Jiangnan-style garden in the capital
حديقة على طراز جيانغنان في العاصمة
and bestow it upon you two siblings.
وأمنحها لكما أيها الشقيقان.
Father,
أب،
I have a request to ask of Father.
لدي طلب أود أن أطلبه من أبي.
Before Mother passed away,
قبل وفاة والدتي،
Heshu, be quiet.
هيشو، اصمت.
Heshu,
هيشو،
what is your request?
ما هو طلبك؟
Speak freely.
تحدث بحرية.
Father,
أب،
Heshu means
هيشو تعني
the palace gift is too much for us two siblings to accept.
إن هدية القصر تفوق قدرتنا نحن الشقيقين على قبولها.
We truly feel unworthy of it.
نشعر حقاً بأننا لا نستحق ذلك.
We only hope Father will grant us permission
كل ما نتمناه هو أن يمنحنا الأب الإذن
to accompany Mother on her final journey.
لمرافقة الأم في رحلتها الأخيرة.
I grant it.
أقر بذلك.
The Crown Prince has arrived.
وصل ولي العهد.
Qi.
تشي.
Yin Zhou is deliberately provoking us.
ين تشو يستفزنا عمداً.
Don't get excited.
لا تنفعل.
Don't fall into his trap.
لا تقع في فخه.
Take it easy.
خذها ببساطة.
The Imperial Concubine Chen has passed away.
توفيت المحظية الإمبراطورية تشين.
Pei is also wearing mourning clothes.
كما أن باي ترتدي ملابس الحداد.
Those who don't know
أولئك الذين لا يعرفون
might even think you were sent by the grassland tribes
قد يظن البعض أنك مرسل من قبل قبائل السهوب
to form an alliance with our Great Xing through marriage.
لتكوين تحالف مع شينغ العظيم من خلال الزواج.
What are you doing here?
ما الذي تفعله هنا؟
Naturally, I've come to pay my respects to the Imperial Concubine Chen.
وبطبيعة الحال، جئت لأقدم احترامي للمحظية الإمبراطورية تشين.
Since it's a condolence visit,
بما أنها زيارة تعزية،
what's the meaning of you wearing red?
ما معنى ارتدائك اللون الأحمر؟
Yin Zhou,
يين تشو,
don't do too much.
لا تفرط في ذلك.
A mere concubine,
إلى محظياتي،
her death is nothing significant.
وفاتها ليست شيئاً ذا أهمية.
Do you expect
هل تتوقع
me to also wear mourning clothes?
هل عليّ أيضاً ارتداء ملابس الحداد؟
Isn't having Pei wear them enough?
ألا يكفي أن ترتديها باي؟
I'll tell Father Emperor.
سأخبر الإمبراطور الأب.
See if you dare to be so arrogant then.
لنرى إن كنت تجرؤ على أن تكون بهذه الغطرسة.
Now that the Imperial Concubine Chen is dead,
والآن بعد وفاة المحظية الإمبراطورية تشين،
why are you still staying by this useless person's side?
لماذا ما زلتِ باقية بجانب هذا الشخص عديم الفائدة؟
[The character indicating offerings to the deceased]
[الرمز الذي يشير إلى القرابين المقدمة للمتوفى]
Qi,
تشي،
Yin Zhou was just trying to sow discord just now.
كان يين تشو يحاول فقط زرع الفتنة الآن.
I'm from your palace.
أنا من قصركم.
I was before,
كنتُ كذلك من قبل،
and I will be in the future.
وسأكون كذلك في المستقبل.
People strive for higher positions.
يسعى الناس إلى شغل مناصب أعلى.
If you insist on going to Yin Zhou's side,
إذا كنت مصراً على الذهاب إلى جانب يين تشو،
how could I stop you?
كيف لي أن أمنعك؟
Qi,
تشي،
Are you hiding something from me?
هل تخفي عني شيئاً؟
What could I possibly be hiding from you?
ما الذي قد أخفيه عنك؟
I know you too well.
أعرفك جيداً.
If you didn't have other plans,
إذا لم تكن لديك خطط أخرى،
you would have definitely joined He Shu just now
كنت ستنضم بالتأكيد إلى هي شو الآن
to plead with the Emperor
أن يتوسل إلى الإمبراطور
for the Imperial Concubine Chen's last wishes.
تحقيقاً لرغبات المحظية الإمبراطورية تشين الأخيرة.
As expected,
كما هو متوقع،
nothing escapes your eyes.
لا شيء يفوت عينيك.
That's right.
هذا صحيح.
I've already planned it out.
لقد خططت لذلك بالفعل.
Tonight, I'll send my mother out of the palace
سأطرد أمي من القصر الليلة.
and then send her back to Jiangnan.
ثم أعدها إلى جيانغنان.
No,
لا،
that's too dangerous.
هذا خطير للغاية.
What if you get caught...
ماذا لو تم القبض عليك...
I will definitely fulfill my mother's last wishes.
سأنفذ بالتأكيد وصية والدتي الأخيرة.
As for this matter,
أما بخصوص هذا الأمر،
you don't have to worry about it.
لا داعي للقلق بشأن ذلك.
Yin Qi has been acting strangely these past two days.
لقد كان يين تشي يتصرف بشكل غريب خلال اليومين الماضيين.
Go tell that person
اذهب وأخبر ذلك الشخص
to keep a close eye on him.
أن نراقبه عن كثب.
Yes.
نعم.
The Imperial Concubine Chen is dead.
ماتت المحظية الإمبراطورية تشين.
What are your plans?
ما هي خططك؟
With such a good opportunity,
مع هذه الفرصة الجيدة،
if I were you,
لو كنت مكانك،
I would have already planned to drive Yin Qi out of the palace.
كنت قد خططت بالفعل لطرد يين تشي من القصر.
For all these years,
طوال هذه السنوات،
Father Emperor has been hinting to Mother Empress
كان الإمبراطور الأب يلمح للإمبراطورة الأم
to pass the crown prince position to me.
أن يسلمني منصب ولي العهد.
But what's the result?
لكن ما هي النتيجة؟
He still wants to use Yin Qi to keep me in check.
لا يزال يريد استخدام طاقة الين كي لإبقائي تحت السيطرة.
You're my son,
أنت ابني،
the only legitimate son of Great Xing.
الابن الشرعي الوحيد لـ"غريت شينغ".
You should naturally inherit the throne.
من الطبيعي أن ترث العرش.
If you had some skills,
إذا كنت تمتلك بعض المهارات،
you would have already become the crown prince by now.
كنت ستصبح ولي العهد بالفعل الآن.
Why would I still need to plan for you?
لماذا سأظل بحاجة إلى التخطيط من أجلك؟
You really are so unpromising.
أنت حقاً شخص غير واعد.
I've already defeated the third and fourth princes,
لقد هزمت بالفعل الأميرين الثالث والرابع،
driving them out of the palace.
طردهم من القصر.
Yin Qi,
يين تشى,
He's just the son of a merchant,
إنه مجرد ابن تاجر،
a lowly and stupid person born to a merchant's daughter.
شخص وضيع وغبي ولد لابنة تاجر.
Apart from reciting poems and painting,
إلى جانب إلقاء القصائد والرسم،
what else can he do?
ماذا يمكنه أن يفعل أيضاً؟
How dare he compete with me?
كيف يجرؤ على منافستي؟
He's just like the Imperial Concubine Chen,
إنه يشبه تماماً المحظية الإمبراطورية تشين،
with just a pretty face.
بوجه جميل فقط.
He...
هو...
Fortunately, the heavens have eyes.
لحسن الحظ، للسماء عيون.
This time,
هذه المرة،
the Imperial Concubine Chen died for a good cause.
ماتت المحظية الإمبراطورية تشين من أجل قضية نبيلة.
The favor she took from the Emperor,
المعروف الذي حصلت عليه من الإمبراطور،
you must take it back from Yin Qi
يجب أن تستعيدها من يين تشي
on my behalf.
نيابة عني.
Don't let me down.
لا تخذلني.
Why does Your Highness look so preoccupied?
لماذا يبدو صاحب السمو مشغولاً للغاية؟
Let this servant serve Your Highness well,
فليخدم هذا الخادم سموكم خير خدمة.
and Your Highness won't be troubled anymore.
ولن يُزعج سموكم بعد الآن.
It's already night.
لقد حلّ الليل بالفعل.
Who's leaving the palace?
من سيغادر القصر؟
This person,
هذا الشخص،
is our Fifth Prince who wants to leave the palace.
هو أميرنا الخامس الذي يريد مغادرة القصر.
The Fifth Prince?
الأمير الخامس؟
Nonsense.
هراء.
He's supposed to escort the Imperial Concubine Chen to the imperial mausoleum tomorrow morning.
من المفترض أن يرافق المحظية الإمبراطورية تشين إلى الضريح الإمبراطوري صباح الغد.
Why would he leave the palace tonight?
لماذا سيغادر القصر الليلة؟
What?
ماذا؟
Don't believe it's me?
ألا تصدق أنني أنا؟
Fifth Prince.
الأمير الخامس.
Are you letting him pass?
هل تسمح له بالمرور؟
Yes.
نعم.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Get lost.
اغرب عن وجهي.
My fifth brother is being restless again.
أخي الخامس أصبح قلقاً مرة أخرى.